# 大家好 去看一下兄弟家的香菇
Hi everyone! Let's go and have a look at my buddy's shiitake mushrooms.
# 就在這下面哦
It's just down there.
# 現在都下雨啦
It's raining now.
# 下雨了也要去
But I'm still going. I don't care.
# 你看 兄弟家的鴨子
Look! My buddy's ducks.
# 都那麼大啦 那麼肥啦 也不宰 (註︰這個「宰」譯作"kill" 或"slaughter"的話有點怪，所以譯作"eat"算了)
They're so big and fat now. But he still doesn't eat them.
# 我都不認識
Can't you even recognize me?
# 不准叫
No barking!
# 你看
Look!
# 這個是花豬哦 (註︰這是這種豬的特式，我想寫清楚點)
The pigs are black-and-white.
# 巴拿馬 (註︰救命，他不是第一次口誤了，這種豬叫「巴馬香豬」，但他總說錯成「巴拿香豬」、「巴拿馬豬」之類)
Panama (speech error of "bama pigs")
# 嗯 還有幾條黑豬
Um! There are several black pigs too.
# 兄弟這裡 上千畝的那個平地喲 (註︰不再太多註譯了，用簡單的方法另大家明白很大就算了，而且其實亦沒錯)
My buddy has tens of hectares of land here.
# 這裡一挖就挖開啦 (註︰「挖」是指挖山)
He opened up the land himself.
# 你看 這裡種的臍橙也有 鴨子也有
Look! Here are navel oranges, and also ducks.
# 這個廠也有 下面還有養豬的(註︰「廠」是經常出現的字，找不到一個很好的翻譯，就是大本營之類的建築物)
Here's a building, and a pigsty down there.
# 上面還有 還有廠房
And also up there. There are also some buildings.
# 放東西的 還有住人的就在上面
They are for storage. The living quarters are also up there.
# 我們去看一下 在上面
Let's take a look, up there.
# 坐下去 快點 坐下去
Sit down! C'mon, sit down!
# 誒 坐下去
Eh? Sit down!
# 這麼聽話的這條狗
What a good dog!
# 好聽話的這條狗
It's such a good dog.
# 小狗
Doggy!
# 對啊 坐下去 不要動哦
Yea, right! Sit down, and don't move!
# 走 走 跟我來
Go, go! Follow me!
# 你看 兄弟家種了 種了很多這個臍橙哦 (註︰加一個"tree"，令下句翻譯更自然)
Look! My buddy has planted, planted a lot of, you know, navel orange trees.
# 差不多種了四五千棵啊 這個臍橙 到處都是
He has planted thousands of them, I mean the navel orange trees. They're everywhere,
# 那上面還有一大片
and also a whole lot of land up there.
# 等一下我們到上面去看一下
We're gonna go up there and have a look in a while.
# 這邊 這邊也開花啦
These, these have already blossomed.
# 應該可以摘啦 (註︰他應該是想說「應該快有臍橙結果可以摘」，不然摘橙樹的花幹啥， 但我不幫他解譯了....)
I think they can be picked.
# 兩年多啦 應該可以
It's like, more than two years already. I think we can,
# 留幾個來 留幾個來吃
reserve a couple, reserve a couple for ourselves.
# 這棵也開花啦
This tree has also blossomed.
# 你看 那一大片都是臍橙樹
Look! All those are navel orange trees over there.
# 兄弟家有豬 豬在這裡
And my buddy's pigs, the pigs are there.
# 那邊 那 那 那裡是可以住人哦
Tha... that, that, that building can be used for accommodation.
# 這裡以前都是山
Here used to be hills and only hills.
# 都被兄弟把它挖 挖出來啦
But my buddy opened, opened it up.
# 我去看一下兄弟家的香菇
Let me take a look at my buddy's shiitake mushrooms.
# 那裡有一點點香菇 我們去看一下
There's a tiny little bit mushrooms. Let's take a look.
# 我們看上面有沒有
Let's see if there's any,
# 好東西吃
good food up there.
# 兄弟還有後花園哦
My buddy has a backyard too.
# (兄)[SIC]種了好多菜 好多花
He has planted a lot of veggies, and a lot flowers here.
# 這是油菜花
This is rapeseed,
# 包菜
and cabbages.
# 這裡面好多哇
There are a lot inside.
# 他這個到處都是香菇 他放的
The mushrooms are everywhere here. He has put them everywhere.
# 上 上面還有很多 等下我帶大家去看一下
There, there are a lot more up there. I'll show you in a while.
# 進裡面去看下
Let's take a look inside,
# 現在
now.
# 哇
Wa!
# 很漂亮哦 這些香菇
These mushrooms are really pretty.
# 這些都是超大啦 超標啦 他都不摘
These are too big. They're already oversize. But he didn't pick them.
# 太懶啦
He's far too lazy.
# 那邊還有
And there too
# 到處都是
Everywhere
# 這裡也是 你看 這裡
Here too. Look! Here.
# 這上面還有哦
And also up there
# 你看 這個很漂亮的哦 這個香菇
Look! It's really pretty, this mushroom.
# 都摘了好多啦
He has already picked a lot.
# 前兩天他還摘了千多斤 這個
He picked hundreds of kilograms here, a couple of days ago.
# 現在等一下 這場雨下完之後哇
And now, another hundreds of kilograms might be coming out,
# 又可能又有一千多斤出來
in a while, after the rain.
# 很快的這個
It grows really fast.
# 一下雨就很多
There are always a lot whenever is rains.
# 要是乾 樹 很乾燥的天氣反而沒有(註︰那個「樹」應該是「燥」的誤讀而已)
There's hardly any if it's jai...I mean, if it's dry.
# 它就要潮濕的天氣 它就長很多出來
It grows a lot when the humidity is high.
# 這邊只是一點點 上面還有好多哇
Here's only a tiny little bit. There are much more up there.
# 你看 到處都是
Look! The mushrooms are everywhere.
# 摘他都不想摘
He is already tired to picking them.
# 摘的他手都乾
It hurts his hands.
# 叫我來幫你摘呀
Why didn't you ask for my help?
# 再去另外一個地方看一下
Let's have a look at another place.
# 就從這裡上去
Let's go up this way.
# 上面還有好多香菇哦
There are also a lot of mushrooms.
# 這公雞
Roosters
# 你看 這裡好多哇
Look! Here are a lot!
# 這有這個樹欄
Here's a wooden handrail.
# 可以喲搞得
Well, it's not bad!
# 兄弟全部把它摘啦 就還有一點點
My buddy has picked all, except a tiny little bit.
# 你看 我都只看到幾個
Look! I can see only a few here.
# 都被他們在摘完啦
They've already picked everything.
# 看一下上面 上面還有哦
Let's take a look up there. There are still more.
# 這些 你看 這個 做了一個樹欄
This is, look! This is, a wooden handrail.
# 這滑滑的 這裡
It's a bit slippery here.
# 你看 這還有一個山塘
Look! Here's a wild pond too.
# 裡面好多魚的哦
There are a lot of fish, you know.
# 你看 這裡還有一大片果園
Look! There's also a huge orchard,
# 往裡面進去都是
from here all the way inside.
# 天晴的時候我們再來
Let's come again on a sunny day,
# 摘點香菇
and pick some mushrooms.
# 這個地方實在太大啦
This place is simply enormous.
# 最少 真的上千畝哇 到處都是
It's at least, really, tens of hectares, the whole area.
# 反正我 下面我還沒走哦
I ah, I haven't been down there,
# 這上面我還沒走 我只是在中間這一段
and neither up there. We've always been here in the middle.
# 啊 現在兩腿發軟啦 我要回去啦
Ah! Now my legs are fatigue. I need to go back.
# 不然晚上都 腳都會發抖的
Otherwise, my legs would be trembling tonight.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.